<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>0xffsec Handbook: The Pentester's Guide on 0xffsec Handbook</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/</link><description>Recent content in 0xffsec Handbook: The Pentester's Guide on 0xffsec Handbook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://0xffsec.com/handbook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FTP (File Transfer Protocol) Service Enumeration</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/services/ftp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/services/ftp/</guid><description>FTP (File Transfer Protocol) At a Glance Default Port: 21 FTP is a standard network protocol used for the transfer of files between a client and a server on a computer network. FTP is built on a client-server architecture using separate control and data connections between the client and the server. FTP authenticates users with a clear-text sign-in protocol, normally in the form of a username and password, but can connect anonymously if the server is configured to allow it.</description></item><item><title>SMTP (Simple Mail Transfer Protocol) Service Enumeration</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/services/smtp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/services/smtp/</guid><description>SMTP (Simple Mail Transfer Protocol) At a Glance Default Ports
SMTP Relay (server-server communication): 25 SMTP Message Submission (client-server communcation): 578 SMTPS (Deprecated): 465 SMTP is a communication protocol for email transmission. It is commonly used to relay and submit messages to another email servers.
SMTP is a delivery protocol only. Meaning mail is &amp;ldquo;pushed&amp;rdquo; to a destination mail server, or next-hop server, as it arrives. Mail is routed based on the destination server, not individual users to which it is addressed.</description></item><item><title>DNS (Domain Name Systems) Service Enumeration</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/services/dns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/services/dns/</guid><description>DNS (Domain Name Systems) At a Glance Default Port: 53 The Domain Name System (DNS) is a hierarchical and decentralized naming system for computers, services, and other resources connected to a network. It associates different information with domain names assigned to each of the participating entities. Most prominently, it translates more easily memorized domain names to the numerical IP addresses needed for identifying computer services and devices with the underlying network protocols.</description></item><item><title>Name/Finger (User Information Protocol) Service Enumeration</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/services/finger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/services/finger/</guid><description>Finger (User Information Protocol) At a Glance Default Port: 79 The Finger User Information Protocol (RFC 1288), is a simple protocol that provides an interface to a remote user information program (RUIP). 1
Banner Grabbing Telnet telnet 10.0.0.3 79 Netcat echo &amp;#34;root&amp;#34; | nc -n 10.0.0.3 79 Enumeration Tools PentestMonkey - finger-user-enum Fast Enum for q in &amp;#39;root&amp;#39; &amp;#39;admin&amp;#39; &amp;#39;user&amp;#39; &amp;#39;0&amp;#39; &amp;#34;&amp;#39;a b c d e f g h&amp;#39;&amp;#34; &amp;#39;|/bin/id&amp;#39;;do echo &amp;#34;FINGER: $q&amp;#34;; finger &amp;#34;$q@10.</description></item><item><title>HTTP/S (Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure) Service Enumeration</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/services/http-https/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/services/http-https/</guid><description>HTTP/S (Hypertext Transfer Protocol / Secure) At a Glance Default Ports
HTTP: 80 HTTPS (HTTP over TLS or SSL): 443 Directory Enumeration Enumerate files and directories. Look for unlinked content, temporary directories, and backups. Widely used tools include dirbuster, gobuster, dirb, and Burp Suite.
Wordlists Included in Kali&amp;rsquo;s wordlists package under /usr/share/wordlists.
/dirbuster/directory-list-2.3-medium.txt ( 1.9M - 220560 lines ) /dirbuster/directory-list-2.3-small.txt ( 709K - 87664 lines ) /dirb/common.</description></item><item><title>Host Discovery</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/discovery-and-scanning/host-discovery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/discovery-and-scanning/host-discovery/</guid><description>Host Discovery At a Glance One of the first steps during the network enumeration is to reduce a set of IPs into a list of active or interesting hosts. Depending on if you are inside the network or scanning remotely, how much noise you can make, and your discovery requirements, different tools, and options are available.
Internal Passive Passive discovery relies on monitoring network layer traffic to detect network topology, services, and applications.</description></item><item><title>Port Scanning</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/discovery-and-scanning/port-scanning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/discovery-and-scanning/port-scanning/</guid><description>Port Scanning At a Glance Port scanning helps you gather additional information about the target by interacting with it. It will give you a better understanding of how different systems interact with each other and host-specific details such as operating systems and available services.
Port Scanners Port scanners can be classified as synchronous and asynchronous.
Synchronous or connection-oriented scanners, like Nmap, wait for the host response to determine if the port is alive.</description></item><item><title>POP (Post Office Protocol) Service Enumeration</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/services/pop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/services/pop/</guid><description>POP (Post Office Protocol) At a Glance Default Ports
POP3: 110 POP3S (POP3 over TLS or SSL): 995 POP, or POP3 (POP version 3), is an application-layer protocol used by email clients to retrieve messages from a mail server. It provides access via IP to mailboxes maintained on a server.
Because POP was designed for temporary Internet connection, clients connect, retrieve messages, store them on the client, and finally delete them from the server.</description></item><item><title>NNTP (Network News Transfer Protocol) Service Enumeration</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/services/nntp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/services/nntp/</guid><description>NNTP (Network News Transfer Protocol) At a Glance Default Ports
NNTP: 119 NNTPS (NNTPS over TLS): 563 NNSP (server-server bulk transfer): 433 NNTP is an application-layer protocol used for transporting Usenet news articles between news servers. Client applications can also inquire, retrieve, and post articles.
Banner Grabbing Telnet telnet 10.0.0.3 119 Netcat nc -n 10.0.0.3 119 openssl 1 openssl s_client -crlf -connect 10.0.0.3:563 Parameters s_client: SSL/TLS client program.</description></item><item><title>MSRPC (Microsoft Remote Procedure Call) Service Enumeration</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/services/msrpc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/services/msrpc/</guid><description>MSRPC (Microsoft Remote Procedure Call) At a Glance Default Ports:
RPC Endpoint Mapper: 135 HTTP: 593 MSRPC is an interprocess communication (IPC) mechanism that allows client/server software communcation. That process can be on the same computer, on the local network (LAN), or across the Internet. Its purpose is to provide a common interface between applications.
Within Windows environments, many server applications are exposed via RPC.
The Microsoft RPC mechanism uses other IPC mechanisms, such as named pipes, NetBIOS or Winsock, to establish communications between the client and the server.</description></item><item><title>NetBIOS (Network Basic Input/Output System) Service Enumeration</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/services/netbios/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/services/netbios/</guid><description>NetBIOS (Network Basic Input/Output System) At a Glance Default Port/s:
NetBIOS Name Service: UDP/137 NetBIOS Datagram Service: UDP/138 NetBIOS Session Service: TCP/139 NetBIOS is a non-routable service that allows applications and computers to communicate over a local area network (LAN).
As an API, NetBIOS relies on network protocols to communicate. In modern networks, NetBIOS runs over TCP/IP via the NetBIOS over TCP/IP protocol or NBT.1
NetBIOS provides three distinct services:</description></item><item><title>SMB (Server Message Block) Service Enumeration</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/services/smb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/services/smb/</guid><description>SMB (Server Message Block) At a Glance Default Ports
SMB over NBT (NetBIOS over TCP/IP): 139 SMB over TCP/IP: 445 SMB is a network communication protocol for providing shared access to files, printers, and serial ports between nodes on a network. It also provides an authenticated IPC (inter-process communication) mechanism.1
Windows SMB Ports and Protocols Originally, in Windows NT, SMB ran on top of NBT (NetBIOS over TCP/IP), which uses ports UDP 137 and 138, and TCP 139.</description></item><item><title>IMAP (Internet Message Access Protocol) Service Enumeration</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/services/imap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/services/imap/</guid><description>IMAP (Internet Message Access Protocol) At a Glance Default Ports
IMAP: 143 IMAPS (IMAP over SSL): 993 IMAP is an application-layer protocol used by email clients to retrieve messages from a mail server. It was designed to manage multiple email clients, therefore clients generally leave messages on the server until the user explicitly deletes them. 1
Banner Grabbing Telnet telnet 10.0.0.3 143 Netcat nc -n 10.0.0.3 143 openssl [^openssl] openssl s_client -connect 10.</description></item><item><title>Exploit Search</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/exploits-search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/exploits-search/</guid><description>Exploit Search Offline searchsploit 1 Note: Periodically update the database with searchsploit -u. Search vulnerabilities based on a Nmap&amp;rsquo;s XML result.
searchsploit --nmap nmap.xml Basic search and copy the exploit the current directory. For more examples, see the manual.
searchsploit afd windows local searchsploit -m 39446 Parameters -u: Check for and install any exploitdb package updates. -m: Copies an exploit to the current working directory.</description></item><item><title>Brute Forcing</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/brute-forcing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/brute-forcing/</guid><description>Brute Forcing At a Glance A brute-forcing attack consists of systematically enumerating all possible candidates for the solution and checking whether each candidate satisfies the problem&amp;rsquo;s statement.
In cryptography, a brute-force attack involves systematically checking all possible keys until the correct key is found. 1
Default Credentials DefaultPassword CIRT.net Password DB Default Router Passwords List Note: SecLists and WordList Compendium also include default passwords lists. Wordlists SecLists - The Pentester&amp;rsquo;s Companion Probable Wordlists WordList Compendium Jhaddix Content Discovery All Google Fuzzing Forum CrackStation&amp;rsquo;s Password Cracking Dictionary Wordlist Generation CeWL 2 cewl example.</description></item><item><title>Steganography</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/steganography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/steganography/</guid><description>Steganography At a Glance Steganography is the art and science of hiding a message, image, or file within another message, image, or file 1
Note: Steganography is used to hide the occurrence of communication. General Determine the file type.
file filename.ext Read file meta-data.
exiftool filename.ext Extract printable characters.
strings -n 6 -e s filename.ext Parameters -n &amp;lt;length&amp;gt;: Print sequence of at least &amp;lt;length&amp;gt; chars long.</description></item><item><title>Reverse Shells</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/shells/reverse-shells/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/shells/reverse-shells/</guid><description>Reverse Shells At a Glance After the exploitation of a remote code execution (RCE) vulnerability, the next step will be to interact with the compromised target. Reverse shells, as opposed to bind shells, initiate the connection from the remote host to the local host. They are especially handy and, sometimes the only way, to get remote access across a NAT or firewall.
The chosen shell will depend on the binaries installed on the target system, although uploading a binary can be possible.</description></item><item><title>Upgrade Simple Shells to Fully Interactive TTYs</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/shells/full-tty/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/shells/full-tty/</guid><description>Upgrade to Fully Interactive TTYs At a Glance More often than not, reverse, or bind shells are shells with limited interactive capabilities. Meaning no job control, no auto-completion, no STDERR output, and, most important, poor signal handling and limited commands support. To fully leverage the shell it is convenient to upgrade to an interactive TTY with extended features.
Note: To check if the shell is a TTY shell use the tty command.</description></item><item><title>How to Escape from Restricted Shells</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/shells/restricted-shells/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/shells/restricted-shells/</guid><description>Escape from Restricted Shells At a Glance Restricted shells limit the default available capabilities of a regular shell and allow only a subset of system commands. Typically, a combination of some or all of the following restrictions are set1:
Using the cd command. Setting or unsetting environment variables. Commands that contain slashes. Filename containing a slash as an argument to the . built-in command. Filename containing a slash as an argument to the -p option to the hash built-in command.</description></item><item><title>Data Exfiltration and Protocol Tunneling</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/exfiltration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/exfiltration/</guid><description>Exfiltration At a Glance Data exfiltration, also called data extrusion or data exportation, is the unauthorized transfer of data from a device or network.1
Encoding Base64 Linux encoding/decoding.
cat filename.ext | base64 -w0 cat filename.ext | base64 -d Parameters -w&amp;lt;col&amp;gt;: wrap encoded lines after &amp;lt;col&amp;gt; character (default 76). -d: decode data. Windows encoding/decoding.
certutil -encode filename.ext output.ext certutil -decode filename.ext output.ext Steganography Cloakify 2 python ./cloakify.py filename.</description></item><item><title>Further Reading</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/further-reading/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/further-reading/</guid><description>Further Reading Practice and Learn 247/CTF CTF 101 CTFlearn CTFtime CryptoHack Embedded Security CTF Hack The Box PentesterLab TryHackMe VulnHub picoCTF pwn.college pwnable.tw Bug Bounty Programs Bugcrowd Facebook Github Google HP HackerOne Intel Microsoft Mozilla Zerodium Books The Hacker Playbook Series Hacking- The Art of Exploitation YouTube Channels Adrian Crenshaw Ben Eater IppSec MalwareAnalysisForHedgehogs Open Security Training Red Team Village Links HighOn.</description></item><item><title>Assets Discovery</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/information-gathering/assets-discovery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/information-gathering/assets-discovery/</guid><description>Assets Discovery At a Glance Assets Discovery helps you identify new targets within the scope. These new seeds, or domains, will broader the attack surface and provide a better understanding of the target and its infrastructure.
Acquisitions Looking for acquisitions may expand the available assets if they are in scope.
Crunchbase Google Wikipedia Note: Look for newer acquisitions and verify it they are still valid ASN Enumeration An Autonomous System Number (ASN) is a unique number assigned to an Autonomous System (AS).</description></item><item><title>CGI - Web Applications Pentesting</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/web-applications/cgi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/web-applications/cgi/</guid><description>Common Gateway Interface At a Glance Common Gateway Interface (CGI) is an interface specification for web servers to execute command-line interface (CLI) programs. These programs also known as CGI scripts or simply CGIs, are commonly executed at the time a request is made and return dynamically generated HTML content.
Most servers expect CGI scripts to reside in a special directory, usually called cgi-bin, to handle the requests correctly and execute the program instead of returning the file content.</description></item><item><title>Command Injection - Web Applications Pentesting</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/web-applications/command-injection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/web-applications/command-injection/</guid><description>Command Injection At a Glance Command injection is an attack in which the attacker executes arbitrary commands on the host OS via a vulnerable application. Command injection attacks are possible when an application passes unsafe user-supplied data to a system shell. 1
Note: Commands are usually executed with the privileges of the vulnerable application. Command Chaining &amp;lt;input&amp;gt;; ls &amp;lt;input&amp;gt;&amp;amp; ls &amp;lt;input&amp;gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp; ls &amp;lt;input&amp;gt;| ls &amp;lt;input&amp;gt;|| ls Note: Also try:</description></item><item><title>CSRF (Cross-Site Request Forgery) - Web Applications Pentesting</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/web-applications/csrf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/web-applications/csrf/</guid><description>Cross-Site Request Forgery At a Glance Cross-Site Request Forgery (CSRF) is an attack that forces an end user into submitting a malicious request on a web application in which they’re currently authenticated.
Unlike XSS, which exploits the trust a user has for a particular site, CSRF exploits the trust that a site has in a user&amp;rsquo;s browser. 1
Note: CSRF is not limited to web applications. An attacker could embed scripting into any document format allowing scripting.</description></item><item><title>File Inclusion and Path Traversal - Web Applications Pentesting</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/web-applications/file-inclusion-and-path-traversal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/web-applications/file-inclusion-and-path-traversal/</guid><description>File Inclusion and Path Traversal At a Glance File Inclusion File inclusion is the method for applications, and scripts, to include local or remote files during run-time. The vulnerability occurs when an application generates a path to executable code using an attacker-controlled variable, giving the attacker control over which file is executed.
There are two different types. Local File Inclusion (LFI) where the application includes files on the current server. And Remote File Inclusion (RFI) where the application downloads and execute files from a remote server.</description></item><item><title>JAR File - What It Is &amp; How to Open One</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/notes/how-to-open-jar-files/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/notes/how-to-open-jar-files/</guid><description>JAR File - What It Is &amp;amp; How to Open One A JAR (Java ARchive) file is a package file format, based on the ZIP file format, used to aggregate many Java class files, metadata and resources (text, images, etc.) into one file for distribution.1
The contents of a JAR file can be extracted using any standard decompression tool, or the jar command line utility.
unzip unzip -d foo foo.jar Parameters -d &amp;lt;dir&amp;gt;: extract files into dir.</description></item><item><title>SMB Protocol Negotiation Failed</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/notes/smb-protocol-negotiation-failed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/notes/smb-protocol-negotiation-failed/</guid><description>SMB Protocol Negotiation Failed Normally SMB takes care of choosing the appropriate protocol for each connection. However, if the offered protocols are out of client&amp;rsquo;s default range, it will return an error message like this:
Protocol negotiation failed: NT_STATUS_IO_TIMEOUT Solution Edit the connection protocol range in the client configuration file.
Add client min protocol and client max protocol settings to /etc/samba/smb.conf under [global].
# /etc/samba/smb.conf [global] client min protocol = CORE client max protocol = SMB3</description></item><item><title>SSH Legacy Key Exchange</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/notes/ssh-legacy-key-exchange/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/notes/ssh-legacy-key-exchange/</guid><description>SSH Legacy Key Exchange Algorithm1 When an SSH client connects to a server, each side offers sets of connection parameters to the other. For a successful connection, there must be at least one mutually compatible set for each parameter.
If the client and the server cannot agree on a mutual set, in this case, the key exchange algorithm, the connection will fail and OpenSSH will return an error message like this:</description></item></channel></rss>