<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notebook</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/notebook/</link><description>Recent content on Notebook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://0xffsec.com/notebook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Host Discovery</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/notebook/discovery-and-scanning/host-discovery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/notebook/discovery-and-scanning/host-discovery/</guid><description>Host Discovery One of the first steps during the network enumeration is to reduce a set of IPs into a list of active or interesting hosts. Depending on if you are inside the network or scanning remotely, how much noise you can make, and your discovery requirements, different tools, and options are available.
Internal Passive Passive discovery relies on monitoring network layer traffic to detect network topology, services, and applications. The process does not generate any network traffic in a network.</description></item><item><title>Port Scanning</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/notebook/discovery-and-scanning/port-scanning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/notebook/discovery-and-scanning/port-scanning/</guid><description>Port Scanning Let&amp;rsquo;s continue narrowing down our attack vector. It is time now to grab your host or list of hosts and scan for open ports and running services.
Port scanners can be categorized between synchronous or connection-oriented and asynchronous or connectionless.
Synchronous scanners, like Nmap, wait for a host response (until the timeout period expires) to determine if the port it&amp;rsquo;s alive. This translates to slower scans, especially on big network ranges, but an accurate port discovery in comparison with connectionless scanners.</description></item><item><title>21 - FTP</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/notebook/enumeration/21-ftp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/notebook/enumeration/21-ftp/</guid><description>FTP (File Transfer Protocol) Default Port: 21 FTP is a standard network protocol used for the transfer of files between a client and a server on a computer network.
FTP is built on a client-server architecture using separate control and data connections between the client and the server. FTP authenticates users with a clear-text sign-in protocol, normally in the form of a username and password, but can connect anonymously if the server is configured to allow it.</description></item></channel></rss>