<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Services on 0xffsec Penetration Testing Book</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/book/services/</link><description>Recent content in Services on 0xffsec Penetration Testing Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://0xffsec.com/book/services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FTP - 21</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/book/services/ftp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/book/services/ftp/</guid><description>FTP File Transfer Protocol.
Default Port: 21
FTP is a standard network protocol used for the transfer of files between a client and a server on a computer network. FTP is built on a client-server architecture using separate control and data connections between the client and the server. FTP authenticates users with a clear-text sign-in protocol, normally in the form of a username and password, but can connect anonymously if the server is configured to allow it.</description></item><item><title>SMTP - 25 / 465 / 587</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/book/services/smtp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/book/services/smtp/</guid><description>SMTP Simple Mails Transfer Protocol.
Default Ports
SMTP Relay (server-server communication): 25 SMTP Message Submission (client-server communcation): 578 SMTPS (Deprecated): 465 SMTP is a communication protocol for email transmission. It is commonly used to relay and submit messages to another email servers.
SMTP is a delivery protocol only. Meaning mail is &amp;ldquo;pushed&amp;rdquo; to a destination mail server, or next-hop server, as it arrives. Mail is routed based on the destination server, not individual users to which it is addressed.</description></item><item><title>DNS - 53</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/book/services/dns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/book/services/dns/</guid><description>DNS Domain Name Systems.
Default Port: 53
The Domain Name System (DNS) is a hierarchical and decentralized naming system for computers, services, and other resources connected to a network. It associates different information with domain names assigned to each of the participating entities. Most prominently, it translates more easily memorized domain names to the numerical IP addresses needed for identifying computer services and devices with the underlying network protocols. 1</description></item><item><title>Finger - 79</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/book/services/finger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/book/services/finger/</guid><description>Finger Finger user information protocol.
Default Port: 79
The Finger User Information Protocol (RFC 1288), is a simple protocol that provides an interface to a remote user information program (RUIP). 1
Banner Grabbing Telnet telnet 10.0.0.3 79 Netcat echo &amp;#34;root&amp;#34; | nc -n 10.0.0.3 79 Enumeration Tools PentestMonkey - finger-user-enum Fast Enum for q in &amp;#39;root&amp;#39; &amp;#39;admin&amp;#39; &amp;#39;user&amp;#39; &amp;#39;0&amp;#39; &amp;#34;&amp;#39;a b c d e f g h&amp;#39;&amp;#34; &amp;#39;|/bin/id&amp;#39;;do echo &amp;#34;FINGER: $q&amp;#34;; finger &amp;#34;$q@10.</description></item><item><title>HTTP/S - 80 / 443</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/book/services/http-https/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/book/services/http-https/</guid><description>HTTP/S Hypertext Transfer Protocol and Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure.
Default Ports
HTTP: 80 HTTPS (HTTP over TLS or SSL): 443 Directory Enumeration As a first step, it is a good idea to enumerate files and directories. Look for unlinked content, temporary directories, and backups. Widely used tools include dirbuster, gobuster, dirb, and the suite Burp.
Wordlists Included in Kali&amp;rsquo;s wordlists package.
James Fisher&amp;rsquo;s 2.3 medium ( 1.</description></item><item><title>POP - 110 / 995</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/book/services/pop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/book/services/pop/</guid><description>POP Post Office Protocol.
Default Ports
POP3: 110 POP3S (POP3 over TLS or SSL): 995 POP, or POP3 (POP version 3), is an application-layer protocol used by email clients to retrieve messages from a mail server. It provides access via IP to mailboxes maintained on a server.
Because POP was designed for temporary Internet connection, clients connect, retrieve messages, store them on the client, and finally delete them from the server.</description></item><item><title>NNTP - 119 / 433 / 563</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/book/services/nntp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/book/services/nntp/</guid><description>NNTP Network News Transfer Protocol.
Default Ports
NNTP: 119 NNTPS (NNTPS over TLS): 563 NNSP (server-server bulk transfer): 433 NNTP is an application-layer protocol used for transporting Usenet news articles between news servers. Client applications can also inquire, retrieve, and post articles.
Banner Grabbing Telnet telnet 10.0.0.3 119 Netcat nc -n 10.0.0.3 119 openssl 1 openssl s_client -crlf -connect 10.0.0.3:563 Parameters s_client: SSL/TLS client program. -crlf: translate a line feed from the terminal into CR+LF.</description></item><item><title>SMB - 139 / 445</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/book/services/smb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/book/services/smb/</guid><description>SMB Server Message Block.
Default Ports
SMB over NetBIOS (NetBIOS over TCP/IP): 139 SMB over TCP/IP: 445 SMB is a network communication protocol for providing shared access to files, printers, and serial ports between nodes on a network. It also provides an authenticated IPC (inter-process communication) mechanism.1
Windows SMB Ports and Protocols Originally, in Windows NT, SMB ran on top of NBT (NetBIOS over TCP/IP), which uses ports UDP 137 and 138, and TCP 139.</description></item><item><title>IMAP - 143 / 993</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/book/services/imap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/book/services/imap/</guid><description>IMAP Internet Message Access Protocol.
Default Ports
IMAP: 143 IMAPS (IMAP over SSL): 993 IMAP is an application-layer protocol used by email clients to retrieve messages from a mail server. It was designed to manage multiple email clients, therefore clients generally leave messages on the server until the user explicitly deletes them. 1
Banner Grabbing Telnet telnet 10.0.0.3 143 Netcat nc -n 10.0.0.3 143 openssl [^openssl] openssl s_client -connect 10.</description></item></channel></rss>