<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Information Gathering on 0xffsec Handbook</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/information-gathering/</link><description>Recent content in Information Gathering on 0xffsec Handbook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://0xffsec.com/handbook/information-gathering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Assets Discovery</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/information-gathering/assets-discovery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/information-gathering/assets-discovery/</guid><description>Assets Discovery # At a Glance # Assets Discovery helps you identify new targets within the scope. These new seeds, or domains, will broader the attack surface and provide a better understanding of the target and its infrastructure.
Acquisitions # Looking for acquisitions may expand the available assets if they are in scope.
Crunchbase Google Wikipedia Note: Look for newer acquisitions and verify it they are still valid ASN Enumeration # An Autonomous System Number (ASN) is a unique number assigned to an Autonomous System (AS).</description></item><item><title>Subdomain Enumeration: The Ultimate Guide</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/information-gathering/subdomain-enumeration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/information-gathering/subdomain-enumeration/</guid><description>Subdomain Enumeration # At a Glance # Sub-domain enumeration is the process of finding sub-domains for one or more domains. It helps to broader the attack surface, find hidden applications, and forgotten subdomains.
Note: Vulnerabilities tend to be present across multiple domains and applications of the same organization. Passive Enumeration # Certificate Transparency Google Dorking DNS Aggregators ASN Enumeration Subject Alternate Name (SAN) Rapid7 Forward DNS dataset Active Enumeration # Brute Force Enumeration Zone Transfer DNS Records Content Security Policy (CSP) Header Tools # Amass 1 # amass enum -passive -d example.</description></item></channel></rss>