<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Enumeration on 0xffsec Penetration Testing Book</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/book/enumeration/</link><description>Recent content in Enumeration on 0xffsec Penetration Testing Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://0xffsec.com/book/enumeration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FTP - 21</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/book/enumeration/ftp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/book/enumeration/ftp/</guid><description>FTP is a standard network protocol used for the transfer of files between a client and a server on a computer network.
FTP is built on a client-server architecture using separate control and data connections between the client and the server. FTP authenticates users with a clear-text sign-in protocol, normally in the form of a username and password, but can connect anonymously if the server is configured to allow it. 1</description></item><item><title>DNS - 53</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/book/enumeration/dns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/book/enumeration/dns/</guid><description>The Domain Name System (DNS) is a hierarchical and decentralized naming system for computers, services, and other resources connected to a network.
It associates different information with domain names assigned to each of the participating entities. Most prominently, it translates more easily memorized domain names to the numerical IP addresses needed for identifying computer services and devices with the underlying network protocols. 1
Banner Grabbing DNS does not provide an information banner per se but BIND DNS exposes its version by default.</description></item><item><title>HTTP/S - 80 / 443</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/book/enumeration/http-https/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/book/enumeration/http-https/</guid><description>Directory Enumeration As a first step, while we browse the web/application, it is a good idea to do some files and directories enumeration, look for unlinked content, temporary directories, and backups.
Widely used tools include dirbuster, gobuster, dirb and the suite Burp.
Wordlists Included in Kali&amp;rsquo;s wordlists package.
James Fisher&amp;rsquo;s 2.3 medium ( 1.9M - 220560 lines )
/usr/share/wordlists/dirbuster/directory-list-2.3-medium.txt
James Fisher&amp;rsquo;s 2.3 small ( 709K - 87664 lines )</description></item><item><title>SMB - 139 / 445</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/book/enumeration/smb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/book/enumeration/smb/</guid><description>SMB is a network communication protocol for providing shared access to files, printers, and serial ports between nodes on a network. It also provides an authenticated IPC (inter-process communication) mechanism.1
Windows SMB Ports and Protocols TL;DR
Port 139: SMB over NBT (NetBIOS over TCP/IP). port 445: SMB directly over TCP/IP. Originally, in Windows NT, SMB ran on top of NBT (NetBIOS over TCP/IP), which uses ports UDP 137 and 138, and TCP 139.</description></item></channel></rss>