<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notes on 0xffsec Penetration Testing Handbook</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/notes/</link><description>Recent content in Notes on 0xffsec Penetration Testing Handbook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://0xffsec.com/handbook/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Open JAR files</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/notes/how-to-open-jar-files/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/notes/how-to-open-jar-files/</guid><description>How to Open JAR Files A JAR (Java ARchive) file is a package file format, based on the ZIP file format, used to aggregate many Java class files, metadata and resources (text, images, etc.) into one file for distribution.1
The contents of a JAR file can be extracted using any standard decompression tool, or the jar command line utility.
unzip unzip -d foo foo.jar Parameters -d &amp;lt;dir&amp;gt;: extract files into dir.</description></item><item><title>SMB Protocol Negotiation Failed</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/notes/smb-protocol-negotiation-failed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/notes/smb-protocol-negotiation-failed/</guid><description>SMB Protocol Negotiation Failed Normally SMB takes care of choosing the appropriate protocol for each connection. However, if the offered protocols are out of client&amp;rsquo;s default range, it will return an error message like this:
Protocol negotiation failed: NT_STATUS_IO_TIMEOUT Solution Edit the connection protocol range in the client configuration file.
Add client min protocol and client max protocol settings to /etc/samba/smb.conf under [global].
# /etc/samba/smb.conf [global] client min protocol = CORE client max protocol = SMB3</description></item><item><title>SSH Legacy Key Exchange</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/notes/ssh-legacy-key-exchange/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/handbook/notes/ssh-legacy-key-exchange/</guid><description>SSH Legacy Key Exchange Algorithm1 When an SSH client connects to a server, each side offers sets of connection parameters to the other. For a successful connection, there must be at least one mutually compatible set for each parameter.
If the client and the server cannot agree on a mutual set, in this case, the key exchange algorithm, the connection will fail and OpenSSH will return an error message like this:</description></item></channel></rss>