<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Web Applications on 0xffsec Penetration Testing Book</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/book/web-applications/</link><description>Recent content in Web Applications on 0xffsec Penetration Testing Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://0xffsec.com/book/web-applications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CGI</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/book/web-applications/cgi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/book/web-applications/cgi/</guid><description>Common Gateway Interface Common Gateway Interface (CGI) is an interface specification for web servers to execute command-line interface (CLI) programs. These programs also known as CGI scripts or simply CGIs, are commonly executed at the time a request is made and return dynamically generated HTML content.
Most servers expect CGI scripts to reside in a special directory, usually called cgi-bin, to handle the requests correctly and execute the program instead of returning the file content.</description></item><item><title>Command Injection</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/book/web-applications/command-injection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/book/web-applications/command-injection/</guid><description>Command Injection Command injection is an attack in which the attacker executes arbitrary commands on the host OS via a vulnerable application. Command injection attacks are possible when an application passes unsafe user-supplied data to a system shell. 1
Commands are usually executed with the privileges of the vulnerable application. Command Chaining &amp;lt;input&amp;gt;; ls &amp;lt;input&amp;gt;&amp;amp; ls &amp;lt;input&amp;gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp; ls &amp;lt;input&amp;gt;| ls &amp;lt;input&amp;gt;|| ls Also try:
Prepending a flag or parameter.</description></item><item><title>CSRF - Cross-Site Request Forgery</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/book/web-applications/csrf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/book/web-applications/csrf/</guid><description>Cross-Site Request Forgery Cross-Site Request Forgery (CSRF) is an attack that forces an end user into submitting a malicious request on a web application in which they’re currently authenticated.
Unlike XSS, which exploits the trust a user has for a particular site, CSRF exploits the trust that a site has in a user&amp;rsquo;s browser. 1
CSRF is not limited to web applications. An attacker could embed scripting into any document format allowing scripting.</description></item><item><title>File Inclusion</title><link>https://0xffsec.com/book/web-applications/file-inclusion-and-path-traversal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://0xffsec.com/book/web-applications/file-inclusion-and-path-traversal/</guid><description>File Inclusion and Path Traversal File Inclusion File inclusion is the method for applications, and scripts, to include local or remote files during run-time. The vulnerability occurs when an application generates a path to executable code using an attacker-controlled variable, giving the attacker control over which file is executed.
There are two different types. Local File Inclusion (LFI) where the application includes files on the current server. And Remote File Inclusion (RFI) where the application downloads and execute files from a remote server.</description></item></channel></rss>